Contact

samtanner11@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/samueltanner (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Amazon Web Services (AWS) Serverless Stack Magnets

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Honors-Awards

Jones + Foster Accelerator Award Recipient

Costco Diversity Scholar Award Recipient

Jones + Foster Accelerator Award Recipient

Coivd Relief Champion

Samuel Tanner

Full Stack Engineer w/ Executive Startup Experience Bend, Oregon, United States

Summary

My career has not followed a linear path and I love that. I've worked as a cold-call salesman, a chocolatier, a chief executive, a designer, a full stack engineer, and a few more roles in between. When I was younger, I did feel a bit lost, jumping from one seemingly unrelated chapter of my life to the next; starting from scratch each time. Now I know that I wasn't lost at all; I have spent the last 12 years developing a very distinctive set of soft and hard skills that allow me to be uniquely adept at turning ideas into realities. I love to build things, moreover, I love to build things with smart, hardworking, and fascinating people.

Experience

Ruvos

Full Stack Engineer May 2023 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Tallahassee, Florida, United States

At Ruvos I have lead the frontend and portions of the backend development for a new AWS service, ObjectVision. The ObjectVision application allows companies to detect anomalous behavior on their AWS resources in near real time.

- Led development of ObjectVision (OVAI), an anomaly detection application used to monitor AWS resources for large agencies eg. AIMS (APHL)
- Architected, deployed and maintained technology stacks using infrastructureas-code managed with the AWS SDK and SST (Serverless Stack Toolkit)
- Built system capable of real-time anomaly detection in a datastream of millions of events per day using OpenSearch, GraphQL, AppSync, Kinesis, EventBridge, DynamoDB, and Lambda (NodeJS & Python)

Designed, built, and deployed ObjectVision frontend using NextJS,
 TailwindCSS, Cognito, FramerMotion, ReactQuery, and MakUi

Upling

Frontend Developer I & II April 2022 - March 2023 (1 year)

Upling automates bookkeeping and financial reporting for small businesses. I was one of two frontend engineers responsible for building and maintaining our frontend application.

- Built entire frontend application with one other developer, servicing thousands of enterprise customers
- Wireframed and implemented custom UI elements for querying, pagination, and filtering large financial data sets
- Integrated Stripe, Finch, Codat, and Auth0 APIs for secure streaming of sensitive financial data from our clients to our financial advisors
- Led data visualization implementation using the VisX graphics library, delivered fully custom financial charts with immediate, query-dependant updates

Mesa Cookware

Co-Founder & Product Manager March 2022 - January 2023 (11 months)

Mesa Cookware is a brand new, premium cookware brand. Our mission is to create essential kitchen tools that can stand the test of time and be handed down generation to generation.

- Created Mesa Cookware brand from scratch, including brand guide, product roll-out, and design of custom kitchen tools
- Partnered with industrial designers and manufacturers to develop and massproduce high-quality cookware
- Designed and manufactured a range of premium kitchen tools, including custom enameled Dutch oven, 5-piece knife set, and cutting board

 Managed complex international logistics and budgets for seamless delivery of all products

BoviSync

Full Stack Web Developer & Project Manager July 2021 - February 2022 (8 months)

- Managed DevOps project that resulted in a 50% decrease of monthly AWS expenditures, and boosting application reliability and speeds
- Wire-framed, built, and deployed mobile-first web app for optimizing cow diets based on on-hand macronutrients using Django, GraphQL, and VueJS
- Spearheaded and delivered multi-year company objective to modernize data visualization service, aggregating data from multiple disparate micro-services using Django, Angular, and PlotlyJS
- Promoted to Engineering Manager led sprints, hiring, and product planning, increased headcount by 30% after departure of CTO and two senior developers

Actualize Coding Bootcamp

7 months

Teaching Assistant & Mentor May 2021 - July 2021 (3 months)

- Taught students how to ideate, architect, and build full stack web applications with CRUD API's
- Focused on teaching proficiency in Ruby, Rails, Javascript, VueJS, and PostgreSQL
- Held private office hours to help students learn new topics or round-out understanding of concepts covered in class

Web Development Student January 2021 - May 2021 (5 months)

• Learned fundamentals and best practices in full-stack web development in areas of project architecture, backend, frontend, and how to effectively selfteach new technologies

- Generated technical requirements and determined the most effective solutions, created wireframes, designed schema, and researched outside resources
- Built and tested the backend, incorporating external APIs
- Created pages and RESTful routes, made web requests to retrieve data, formatted and styled results, incorporated libraries and themes

Joe Chocolate Co.
Co-Founder & CEO
March 2016 - December 2020 (4 years 10 months)
Seattle, Washington, United States

Naturally caffeinated dark chocolate. Locally produced, nationally distributed, internationally enjoyed.

- Started as a undergraduate class project, grew to a 7-figure ARR business with wholesale, retail, food-service operations
- Custom built majority of SquareSpace website using CSS, HTML, and vanilla JS

Built and maintained CRM, fulfillment, and sales forecasting system using AirTable and other GUI relational databases

- Drove wholesale business using my own CRM platform, enabling nationwide fulfillment to retailers like Whole Foods, REI, and Nordstrom
- Managed wholesale and retail operations, employing over 20 staff members
 Oversaw construction and opened retail facility in Pike Place Market, serving
 50K+ customers per year

Caveman Dirtbag Sponsorship
Founder
March 2018 - May 2020 (2 years 3 months)
Seattle, Washington, United States

Fueling thru-hikers on the Pacific Crest Trail.

Created business co-op to sponsor thru-hikers on the PCT

- •Partnered with Patagonia Seattle, Arc'teryx, Enlightened Equipment, and other outdoor brands
- •Selected 2-4 hikers each year to receive cash, gear, and food in carepackages
- •Recognized as preeminent sponsorship amongst thru-hikers and received hundreds of applications each year
- •Sponsored hikers from countries including Brazil, New Zealand, and Israel

Peach

Business Development Associate August 2016 - November 2016 (4 months)

Seattle, Washington, United States

- •Performed sales cycle from discovery, to cold calling, to activation of lunch delivery program
- •Onboarded 30+ businesses onto Peach lunch delivery platform including two of Seattle's largest hospitals, JP Morgan, and Weyerhaeuser's headquarters
- Developed best practices for activating healthcare providers

CardSwapper

Co-Founder & CEO

February 2013 - June 2016 (3 years 5 months)

Seattle, Washington, United States

The world's first peer-to-peer trading platform for unused and unwanted gift cards

- Hired and managed team to develop, and launch application gift card trading application on web and iOS app store
- Raised seed funding from Jones + Foster Accelerator and from private investors
- Wrote, submitted, and received patent from the United States Patent and Trademark Office for novel methods of digital gift card exchange

• Partnered with nations largest gift card liquidation platform to launch cash-forcards feature

University of Washington - School of Music Student Visual and Audio Archiver October 2013 - May 2016 (2 years 8 months) Seattle, Washington, United States

- Recorded, live-mixed, and produced live classical, jazz, choral, and orchestral performances in high-fidelity
- Self-taught Logic Pro, Audacity, and Premiere Pro to increase quality of archived media
- •Hired independently by graduate students to produce thesis performances due to quality of work

Tango Card, Inc.
Social Networking Intern
June 2013 - September 2013 (4 months)
Seattle, Washington, United States

- Managed Facebook, Twitter, and Linkedin social profiles via Hootsuite
- Deployed social marketing strategies focused on increasing relevance amongst key demographics
- Nearly doubled Twitter following using unpaid-marketing strategies

Education

University of Washington - Michael G. Foster School of Business Bachelor of Arts - Business Administration, Focus in Entrepreneurship, Entrepreneurship/Entrepreneurial Studies · (2012 - 2016)

Actualize Coding Bootcamp

Computer Software Engineering · (2021 - 2021)